NETWORK ENGINEER AND PROJECT MANAGER

Professional Summary

I am a Network Engineer and IT Project Manager with experience working as both an internal employee and external consultant. One of my strongest attributes is the ability to combine technical expertise with communication skills and strategy for maximum business effectiveness. From a technical standpoint I have designed and implemented networks for financial institutions, medical institutions, office buildings, and municipalities while from a management standpoint I have experience supervising budgets, schedules, employees, and sub-contractors.

IT Industry Certifications

CCNP - Cisco Certified Network Professional

MCSE - Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert Server Infrastructure

VCP - VMWare Certified Professional 5 - Data Center Virtualization

CCNA - Cisco Certified Network Associate

MCSA - Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Server 2012

Skills

Network Engineering, IT Management, Active Directory, Cloud Computing, IT Security, Routers, Switches, VoIP, Automation, Analytics, Systems Engineering, Virtualization, SaaS, IaaS, Firewalls, VPN's, Disaster Recovery, IT Infrastructure

Professional Experience

Network Engineer and Project Manager 09/2013 to Current Zayo Group

Innovative Business Systems is a Microsoft Gold Partner based in Easthampton, Massachusetts. With clients across New England, IBS specializes in designing and deploying comprehensive IT infrastructure solutions for financial and medical institutions. While at Innovative I serve as a Tier 3 Technical Resource for other staff as well as Project Manager for our financial clients. Below are some of the IT infrastructure and application solutions I have implemented:

Deployed a network and server infrastructure upgrade for a regional savings bank with 11 branch locations. Built and implemented a new VMware environment with a HP 3Par SAN and HP ESXi hosts. Migrated Xen server virtual machines into the vSphere environment. Designed and installed a backup system for the entire bank including the DR site.

Performed a Microsoft Exchange 2007 to 2013 migration for a 300-mailbox credit union in the western part of the state with 8 physical locations.

Designed and deployed a new IT infrastructure, servers and networks, for an auditing company with a remote workforce. The project included implementing a backup solution and migrating data, services, and applications from legacy servers to a new VMware environment. Migrated email onto a third party hosted Exchange service.

Managed the core processor banking software conversion for a 5 location financial institution in the western part of Massachusetts. In addition, managed third party fiber installation. Implemented Cisco ASA's and VPN site-to-site tunnels across locations along with redundant VPN tunnels from secondary ISPs.

Designed and implemented an antivirus solution for a regional savings bank in the northern part of the state spanning 9 physical locations. Implemented the solution to include information governance controls such as USB blocking and content filtering. Integrated the solution with the Microsoft Active Directory structure spanning all 9 physical locations in separate Active Directory Sites.

Network Engineer 01/2012 to 09/2013 Amita Health

Planned, designed, configured, and managed the installation of the technology infrastructure, phone system, and servers for an office building at 6 Institute Road Worcester, MA which included:

â€∢

- Designing a Windows 2008 Network supporting three separate organizations within the same building and off of the same demarcation point
- Managing electric sub-contractor to install electric throughout the building in support of the computer network and telephone network
- Running and terminating Cat6 cable throughout the building and into the MDF to meet building and electric code requirements
- Implementing VLAN (virtual LANS) on network switches to segregate data and voice traffic within the building as well as traffic between the organizations
- Installing Cisco Power over Ethernet Security Cameras, the PoE switch, and the node that manages the cameras
- Designing and installing board room AV system and a sound system including speakers, a sound board, and wireless microphones for the public events room
- Deploying and configuring Windows 2008, server shares, Active Directory, and Group Policy for all three organizations

Planned, designed, configured, and managed the installation of a new server based Local Area Network for the Town of Warren, MA which included:

â€∢

- Implemented VLANs to remain in compliance with State of Massachusetts privacy regulations for municipalities
- Configured Port Security on switches to allow one static MAC address connection on end user computers with sensitive information
- Configured a Windows 2008 Domain, Active Directory, and Group Policy for the different departments
- Designed a new IP addressing scheme including static IP addresses and DHCP (dynamic host control protocol) for the new Local Area Network

Lead Network Engineer for a 1600 person organization

Managed two full-time and one part-time direct reports

Designed and deployed a unified Windows Server 2008 Network across four separate buildings while migrating off of a Novell IPX network in an operational environment. This included:

â€∢

- Configuring a new Windows 2008 Active Directory and Group Policy for the network
- Installing domain controllers at all three buildings and designed the network for as little VPN traffic as necessary regarding authentication and file sharing between buildings
- Installing new gigabit switches in support of the network Implementing STP and port security to eliminate communication outages caused by broadcast storms
- Configuring Remote Desktop so front line IT support could remote across buildings for faster resolution times to user requests
- Deployed a Cisco wireless network on the ESS model

Managed a \$500,000 annual budget, all computer networks, and three technology personnel for a 1600 person, four building, school district. Planned, presented at Town Committee meetings, and successfully led an effort for town tax payers to pass a resolution to spend \$300,000 upgrading the IT at one of the elementary schools. Managed customer service and support for users within the district. Interfaced with the public to raise support and funds for technology in the district.

Education

Master of Science : Information Technology 2015 University of Massachusetts Lowell City , State $3.925\ GPA$

Attending part-time while working full-time since Summer of 2013. Expected graduation in Summer 2015.

Coursework in: Network Infrastructures; Virtual Systems; Information Security; Cloud Computing; Advanced Cloud Computing; Agile and Iterative Project Management; Information Technology Management

The Master's of Science degree program is designed to provide both a principled and applied exposure toward designing, managing and deploying networked systems of computers. The program places emphasis on practical skills based on Linux/Unix, Windows and Apple platforms, but also teaches general principles along with their technical and ethical foundations. Courses include general system administration, virtualization technologies, core networking, cloud computing, routing, large scale application deployment, mobile computing, security analysis and regulatory compliance. Working professionals completing the degree program are better-prepared to fill senior level IT management and consulting positions as well as information security and IT strategic planning functions.

Bachelor of Arts 2010 Wesleyan University City, State

High School Diploma 2006 St. John's High School City, State

Professional Affiliations

Institute of Electrical and Electronics EngineersÂ

â€∢IEEE Systems Council: Communications Society Membership and Information Theory Society Membership Work Examples

I've included three attachments to this resume which demonstrate my professional experience and background:

1. Wide Area Network Design for a Financial Institution

This document is a Wide Area Network Design for a financial institution that I planned and designed. The name of the organization and some of the details have been censored to preserve the anonymity of the organization. $\hat{a} \in A$

2. Exchange 2007-2013 Mailbox Migration Technical Tutorial

This document is an original technical tutorial that I wrote for Microsoft Exchange migrations and is based on my own research and experience performing Microsoft Exchange upgrades.

3. Using the Cloud to Maximize Operations

This document is a paper I wrote to describe the benefits of cloud computing for an organization from an operations perspective. It details my experience moving the school district to a cloud computing model that I initiated and managed while I was the Technology Director for the organization.